<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Design on Kei's Blog</title><link>https://moonorange.github.io/categories/software-design/</link><description>Recent content in Software Design on Kei's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://moonorange.github.io/categories/software-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Designing Data-Intensive Applications</title><link>https://moonorange.github.io/posts/software_design/ddia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://moonorange.github.io/posts/software_design/ddia/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s this article about This is my notes of a book called Designing Data-Intensive Applications.
Chapter3 Storage and Retrieval
SSTables and LSM Trees Sorted String Tables and Log-Structured Merge Trees are still used in some database.
As a rule of thumb, LSM Trees are faster for writes but slower for read than B-Tree index.
B-Trees The B-Tree is the most widely used indexing structure.
It stores data in a balanced tree like image below, thus searching data can be done in O(logN).</description></item><item><title>OOP Random Notes</title><link>https://moonorange.github.io/posts/software_design/oop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://moonorange.github.io/posts/software_design/oop/</guid><description>Intro Random notes of relating OOP Terminology Parameter A parameter is a named variable passed into a function. Parameter variables are used to import arguments into functions. The difference between parameters and arguments Function parameters are the names listed in the function&amp;rsquo;s definition. Function arguments are the real values passed to the function. Parameters are initialized to the values of the arguments supplied. MDN Parameter Override Overriding a method means</description></item><item><title>デザインパターン</title><link>https://moonorange.github.io/posts/software_design/design_patterns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://moonorange.github.io/posts/software_design/design_patterns/</guid><description>デザインパターンとは 過去のソフトウェア設計者が発見し編み出した設計ノウハウを蓄積し、名前をつけ、再利用しやすいように特定の規約に従ってカタロ</description></item><item><title>デザインパターン２</title><link>https://moonorange.github.io/posts/software_design/design_patterns_2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://moonorange.github.io/posts/software_design/design_patterns_2/</guid><description>8 Abstract Factory 抽象的な部品を組み合わせて抽象的な製品を作る 実装 抽象的な部品 Item link と tray のスーパークラス link と tray を同一視するためのクラス caption field はこの項目の見出</description></item></channel></rss>